Guide to the Lorin Edgar Kerr Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Other Professional Activities, 1944-1978; Series II; 10 linear feet (24 boxes)
  - District of Columbia Department of Public Health, Public Health Advisory Council
    - Committees
      - Medical Care and Hospitals
        - Subcommittees
          - Hospitals and Extended Care Facilities
            - Report, undated (Box 34, Folder 171)
          - Laboratory Services: correspondence and minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 172)
          - Manpower: correspondence and minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 173)
          - Pharmacy Services: correspondence and minutes, 1966-1968 (Box 34, Folder 174)
          - Physicians' Services: correspondence and minutes, 1966-1968 (Box 34, Folder 175)
      - Mental Health
        - Correspondence and reports re: alcoholism, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 176)
        - Correspondence, memoranda and report, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 177)
      - Mental Retardation
        - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 178-179)
        - Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 180)
  - District of Columbia Public Health Association
    - Committee minutes and memoranda, 1963-1964, 1968-1972 (Box 35, Folder 181)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 35, Folder 182)
    - Lists of members and officers, 1963-1972 (Box 35, Folder 183)
    - Suggested program, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 184)
    - Agenda and minutes of Governing Council, 1964-1968 (Box 35, Folder 185)
    - Memoranda re: Governing Council, 1965-1970 (Box 35, Folder 186)
    - Correspondence and memoranda re: material for affiliates, 1966-1972 (Box 35, Folder 187)
    - Constitution and bylaws, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 188)
    - Resolutions and policy statements, 1967-1968, undated (Box 35, Folder 189)
    - Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 36, Folder 190)
    - Program, minutes and speech text for annual meetings, 1968-1969, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 191)
    - Seminar program, 1969 September 18 (Box 36, Folder 192)
    - Newsletters, 1969 October, 1972 September-October (Box 36, Folder 193)
    - Correspondence re: chaptership, 1969-1971 (Box 36, Folder 194)
    - Memoranda and related material re: Conference on Association Functions, Organization and Relationships (C.A.F.O.R.), 1969-1971 (Box 36, Folder 195)
    - Agenda and minutes of Governing Council, 1969-1972 (Box 36, Folder 196)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 36, Folder 197)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 198)
    - Position papers re: drugs and drug abuse, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 199)
    - Correspondence and reports re: Task Force on Food Sanitation Program, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 200)
    - Report and summary re: Special Ad Hoc Committee for Mental Health, 1971-1972 (Box 36, Folder 201)
  - Group Health Association of America
    - Background Material
      - Minutes, 1952-1954 (Box 36, Folder 202)
      - Minutes, report and releases re: conferences between Association of Labor Health Administrators and Community Health Federation of America, 1954-1956 (Box 36, Folder 203)
      - Bylaws, 1954-1957 (Box 36, Folder 204)
      - Correspondence and lists re: membership committee, 1954-1958 (Box 36, Folder 205)
      - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 36, Folder 206)
      - Correspondence and minutes re: Committee on Business Statistics, 1955-1956 (Box 36, Folder 207)
      - Minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 36, Folder 208)
      - Correspondence and background material re: "Directory of Union Health Centers", 1955-1958 (Box 36, Folder 209)
      - Correspondence and background material re: medical services report form, 1956-1957 (Box 37, Folder 210)
      - Newsletters, 1956-1957 (Box 37, Folder 211)
      - Correspondence, minutes and background material re: special labor meeting, 1957 March (Box 37, Folder 212)
      - Correspondence, 1957 January-December (Box 37, Folder 213-214)
      - Minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 37, Folder 215)
      - Statement re: membership committee (L.E.K.), 1958 November 15 (Box 37, Folder 216)
      - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 217)
      - Correspondence re: National Conference on Labor Health Services, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 218)
      - Correspondence and background material re: merger between American Labor Health Association and Group Health Federation of America, 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 219)
      - President's report, 1959 May (Box 37, Folder 220)
      - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 221)
      - Request for publication, National Conference on Labor Health Services, 1959-1960 (Box 37, Folder 222)
      - G.H.A.A. articles of incorporation and bylaws, 1959-1969, undated (Box 37, Folder 223)
      - Pamphlets and leaflet, undated (Box 37, Folder 224)
    - General Papers
      - Correspondence
        - General correspondence, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 225)
        - Correspondence and background material re: Uniform Medical Practice Act, 1963 March (Box 38, Folder 226)
        - General correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 227)
        - Correspondence and background material re: "Guidelines of Reimbursement for Group Practice Prepayment Plans", 1966 October (Box 38, Folder 228)
        - Correspondence and background material re: proposed labor-federal government health program, 1966 October-November (Box 38, Folder 229)
        - General correspondence, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 230)
        - Correspondence and background material re: demonstration grant to establish community group practice programs, 1967-1968, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 231)
        - Correspondence and background material re: mortgage insurance for hospital construction, 1968 January-July (Box 38, Folder 232)
        - Correspondence and background material re: Group Practice Medical Services Assistance Act, 1968 January-August (Box 38, Folder 233)
        - General correspondence, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 234)
        - Correspondence and background material re: Rhode Island Group Health Association, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 235)
        - General correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 38, Folder 236-238)
        - General correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box 39, Folder 239-240)
      - Administrative files
        - Annual membership meetings
          - Minutes and background material, 1968-1971, 1974-1975 (Box 39, Folder 241-242)
        - Board of Directors
          - Correspondence and minutes, 1965-1972, 1973 June-August (Box 39, Folder 243-248)
          - Correspondence and minutes, 1973 September-Dec, 1974-1976 (Box 40, Folder 249-252)
        - Executive Committee
          - Correspondence and minutes, 1963-1972 (Box 40, Folder 253-257)
          - Correspondence and minutes, 1973-1976 (Box 41, Folder 258-259)
    - Committees
      - Ad Hoc Committee on Dual Choice: "summary notes", 1967 November (Box 41, Folder 260)
      - Bylaws Committee: correspondence, minutes and background material, 1971-1974 (Box 41, Folder 261)
      - Committee on Group Practice Prepayment Plans
        - Correspondence, minutes and background material, 1965-1966 Apr, 1966 May-1967 (Box 41, Folder 262-263)
      - Committee on Optometry
        - Correspondence, background material and draft, 1958-1959 (Box 41, Folder 264)
        - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 265)
        - Correspondence and drafts, 1961-1963 (Box 41, Folder 266)
        - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 267)
        - Correspondence and drafts, 1965-1967 (Box 41, Folder 268)
        - Correspondence and drafts, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 269)
      - Committee on Standards and Accreditation for Group Practice Prepayment Plans: correspondence and minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 42, Folder 270)
      - Group Health Foundation: founding papers, bylaws and minutes, 1962-1968 (Box 42, Folder 271)
      - Medical Directors' Division: correspondence, minutes and bylaws, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 272)
      - Medical Rights Committee: correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 42, Folder 273)
      - Membership Committee
        - Correspondence, minutes and application material, 1961-1964, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 274)
        - Correspondence, minutes and application material, 1973-1975 (Box 42, Folder 275)
      - Occupational Health Committee: correspondence and background material, 1959-1966 (Box 42, Folder 276)
      - Policy Review Committee: correspondence and background material, 1969-1970 (Box 42, Folder 277)
      - Professional Services Committee: correspondence, 1968 (Box 42, Folder 278)
    - Conferences
      - Group Health Institute
        - Proceedings, 1961-1962 (Box 42, Folder 279-280)
        - Proceedings, 1963-1965 (Box 43, Folder 281-283)
        - Preliminary program, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 284)
        - Proceedings, 1967 (Box 43, Folder 285)
        - Correspondence and Proceedings, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 286)
        - Correspondence, Proceedings and program, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 287)
        - Correspondence, Proceedings and list, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 288)
        - Correspondence, Proceedings and miscellaneous material, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 289)
        - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 290)
        - Proceedings, 1973-1974 (Box 43, Folder 291-292)
        - Program and Proceedings, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 293)
      - Conference of American Medical Association, Committee on Insurance Plan Accreditation: correspondence and background material, 1967 January-February (Box 44, Folder 294)
      - Conference on Comprehensive Medical Care: correspondence and background material, 1967 March (Box 44, Folder 295)
      - National Conference on Private Health Insurance: speeches and background material, 1967 September (Box 44, Folder 296)
      - National Citizens Conference on the Rehabilitation of the Handicapped: correspondence, minutes and background material, 1968 April-June (Box 44, Folder 297)
      - Lawyers Conference on Health Maintenance Organizations: Proceedings, 1971 August (Box 44, Folder 298)
      - Health Maintenance Organizations Short Term Training Course: programs and background material, 1971 October-December (Box 44, Folder 299)
      - National Conference on Rural Health Maintenance Organizations: correspondence and program, 1974 June-July (Box 44, Folder 300)
    - Miscellany
      - Group Health and Welfare News, 1962-1969, 1972-1976 (Box 44, Folder 301-303)
      - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1971 (Box 44, Folder 304)
  - Howard University
    - Correspondence, course outlines and reading lists, 1960 (Box 45, Folder 305)
    - Outline, correspondence and schedules, 1966-1976, undated (Box 45, Folder 306)
  - National Institutes on Rehabilitation and Health Services
    - General Papers
      - Report, 1960 January (Box 45, Folder 307)
      - Institute manual, 1961 (Box 45, Folder 308)
      - Bylaws and certificate of incorporation, 1961-1966 (Box 45, Folder 309)
      - Minutes and agendas, 1961-1966 (Box 45, Folder 310)
      - Memoranda and correspondence, 1961-1969, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 311)
      - Reports re: worker rehabilitation, 1962, 1967 (Box 45, Folder 312)
      - Proposed objectives and program, 1963 January (Box 45, Folder 313)
      - Financial papers, 1963-1964, 1966 (Box 45, Folder 314)
      - Report of director, 1964 August 11 (Box 45, Folder 315)
      - Grant request re: Information and Communication Service Project, 1964 (Box 45, Folder 316)
      - List of trustees, consultants and committee members, 1965 June (Box 45, Folder 317)
      - Correspondence and prospectus re: National Labor Health Conference, 1966 April 29 (Box 45, Folder 318)
      - Personnel policies and related correspondence, 1966 Apr, June (Box 45, Folder 319)
      - Memorandum re: proposed union contract for office and professional employees, 1966 August 31 (Box 45, Folder 320)
      - News releases, 1967, 1970, undated (Box 45, Folder 321)
      - Statement and background material re: rating disability under workmen's compensation, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 322)
      - Report of the National Workshop on Rehabilitation and Workmen's Compensation, 1971 April 23-24 (Box 45, Folder 323)
      - Correspondence re: Bell Greve Memorial Award 1971 Oct (Box 45, Folder 324)
    - Committees and Projects
      - Committee on Rehabilitation Services in a Labor Health Center
        - Sidney Hillman Health Center Project
          - Drafts of project design, 1960-1961 (Box 45, Folder 325)
          - Grant application, budget proposals and correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 45, Folder 326)
          - Correspondence and memoranda, 1960-1963 (Box 45, Folder 327)
          - News release and reprints, 1960-1964 (Box 45, Folder 328)
          - Progress reports, 1961-1963 (Box 46, Folder 329)
          - Report, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 330)
        - New York City Labor-Rehabilitation Liaison Project
          - Proposal drafts and outline, 1962-1963 (Box 46, Folder 331)
          - Correspondence, minutes and news release, 1963 (Box 46, Folder 332)
          - Progress report, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 333)
        - Mental Health Rehabilitation for a Union Population Project
          - Grant proposal, 1963 June (Box 46, Folder 334)
          - Progress report, 1964-1965 (Box 46, Folder 335)
      - Research Program Committee
        - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 336)
        - Report and discussion text, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 337)
      - Advisory Committee on Public Relations and Publications: memorandum, 1965 November 29 (Box 46, Folder 338)
      - Mental Health Program Planning Committee: correspondence and memorandum, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 339)
      - Occupational Health Committee: correspondence, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 340)
- Writings, 1943-1978; Series III; 1 linear feet (3 boxes)
  WRITINGS is arranged chronologically. Undated material is filed at the end of the series.
  - "Labor and Health Problems," Labor Council-C.I.O.: speech text, 1943 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - "Co-ordinating School-Community Health Education," Ohio Schools: reprint, 1944 April (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - "The Food and Health Needs of the Elementary School Child," Nutrition for Health: reprint, 1944 April (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - "Coordinating Health Education," Public Health Nursing: reprint, 1944 September (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - "A Survey of 1800 Cases of Syphilis in a Suburban and Rural Community, Ingham County, Michigan," with C.D. Barrett, The Journal of the Michigan State Medical Society: reprint, 1944 October (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - "The Miners Have an Alternative to Socialized Medical and Hospital Care," Hospitals: reprint, 1951 January (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - "Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis," Industrial Medicine and Surgery: reprint, correspondence and related material, 1956 August (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - "Birth: Problems Associated with the Creation of Effective Community Official Health Services," American Journal of Public Health and The Nation's Health: reprint, 1957 November (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - "Community Health Services: The Addition of Essential Health Services," National Conference on Labor Health Services, Washington, D.C.: speech text, 1958 June 16-17 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - "Vision Services for the Worker and His Family," The Optometric Weekly: reprint, 1958 September 4 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - "A Labor Health Program: Its Development and Services," Physical Therapy Review: reprint, 1960 November (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - "A Labor-Health Program for Rehabilitation," Journal of Rehabilitation: reprint, 1962 July-August (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - "An American Labor Health Program," Publication in Honor of Director of Public Health, Karl Evang, on His 60th Birthday: reprint, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - "Rehabilitation Needs and Organized Labor," Public Health Reports: reprint, 1964 December (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - "Lay Membership in the American Public Health Association," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, 1965 November (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - "Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis," University of West Virginia, Morgantown, West Virginia: correspondence, program and newsclippings, 1967 May 18-20 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - "Medical Care Innovations of the U.M.W.A. Welfare and Retirement Fund," Public Health Service-Labor Seminar on Consumer Health Services, Washington, D.C.: speech text, agenda and list of participants, 1968 January 22-23 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - "Coal Workers and Pneumoconiosis," Archives of Environmental Health: reprint and correspondence, 1968 April (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - "Desire, Expectation and Reality in a Union Health Program," New England Journal of Medicine: reprint, correspondence and background material, 1968 May 23 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - "Medical Care Innovations of the United Mine Workers of America Welfare and Retirement Fund," Public Health Reports: reprint, 1968 July (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - "Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis: The Road to Dusty Death," 45th Consecutive Constitutional Convention of the United Mine Workers of America, Denver: speech text and reprints, 1968 September 10 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - "Occupational Pneumoconiosis of Coal Miners as a Public Health Problem," Virginia State Health Department and Wise County Medical Society, Wise, Virginia: speech text, program and correspondence, 1968 September 21 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - "Prepaid Group Practice: Essential to Medical Care Quality and Economy," Journal of the National Medical Association: reprint, 1968 September (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - "Occupational Health and Safety," Medical Tribune: editorial and correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - "The Poverty of Affluence," Long Range Planning Conference, American College of Radiology: speech text and correspondence, 1969 September 27 (Box 47, Folder 24)
  - "The Future of Physician/Patient Relations," WAMU-FM: correspondence and schedule, 1969 November-December (Box 47, Folder 25)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: introduction and topical outline, 1969 December 1 (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - "Occupational Health: No Longer an Insoluble Dilemma," Prism Magazine: text and correspondence, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 27)
  - Congressional testimony: texts, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 28)
  - Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis in the United States, with others, Academy Press: correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 47, Folder 29)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: text and related material, 1970 February 1, March 15 (Box 47, Folder 30)
  - "The Union Looks at Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis," American Industrial Health Conference, Chicago: speech text and correspondence, 1970 April 15 (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - "The Dust Problem in the Coal Mines - Labor's Viewpoint," American Industrial Hygiene Conference, Detroit: speech text and correspondence, 1970 May 12 (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: texts, 1970 (Box 47, Folder 31)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: text and related material, 1970 September 15, November 1 (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - "The UMWA Looks at Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis," Journal of Occupational Medicine: reprint, 1970 September (Box 48, Folder 33)
  - "Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis in an Affluent Society," Public Health Reports: reprint and correspondence, 1970 October (Box 48, Folder 34)
  - "The Role of the United Mine Workers of America and the Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act": text, 1970 Fall (Box 48, Folder 35)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: text, 1970 December 1 (Box 48, Folder 36)
  - "Physicians' Involvement with Industrial Productivity," The Journal of the Tennessee Medical Association: reprint, speech text, correspondence and program, 1970 December (Box 48, Folder 37)
  - "Black Lung Questions and Answers," United Mine Workers Journal: texts, 1970-1971 (Box 48, Folder 38)
  - Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis in the United States, with others, Academy Press: chapter drafts, 1970-1971 (Box 48, Folder 39)
  - Congressional testimony: texts, 1970-1971 (Box 48, Folder 40)
  - The Legislative Fight:, page proofs (Box 48, Folder 41)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: drafts, notes and related material, 1970-1974 (Box 48, Folder 42)
  - "Black Lung Disease and General Mine Safety," University of West Virginia, Morgantown, West Virginia: lecture outline and correspondence, 1971 February 5 (Box 48, Folder 43)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: texts, 1971 March 15, April 1 (Box 48, Folder 44)
  - "Black Lung Compensation," Drift, Kentucky: speech outline and correspondence, 1971 April 1 (Box 48, Folder 45)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: draft and text, 1971 May 15, August 1 (Box 48, Folder 46)
  - "Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis," Journal of the American Medical Association: reprint and correspondence, 1971 May 24 (Box 48, Folder 47)
  - "The United Mine Workers of America Look at Public Health," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, 1971 May (Box 48, Folder 48)
  - "Occupational Health: The Next Major National Health Problem," The Sciences: reprint, 1971 August-September (Box 48, Folder 49)
  - "Black Lung," Harvard Medical School, Boston: speech outline and correspondence, 1971 November 2 (Box 48, Folder 50)
  - Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis in the United States, with others, Academy Press: correspondence, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 51)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: texts and clippings, 1972 February 15, March 1 (Box 48, Folder 52)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: texts, drafts and clippings, 1972 April 1, June 1 (Box 48, Folder 53)
  - "The Neglect of Occupational Health: A National Scandal," National Tuberculosis and Respiratory Disease Association: speech text, program and correspondence, 1972 May 23 (Box 48, Folder 54)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: texts, drafts and clippings, 1972 July 1, August 1 (Box 48, Folder 55)
  - "Your Health Column," United Mine Workers Journal: text, drafts and clippings, 1972 December (Box 48, Folder 56)
  - "Occupational Health," Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania: correspondence and schedule, 1973 April 19 (Box 48, Folder 57)
  - "Occupational Health - A Discipline in Search of a Mission," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, speech texts, program and correspondence, 1973 May (Box 48, Folder 58)
  - "APHA and the Affiliates," American Journal of Public Health: reprint and speech text, 1973 October (Box 48, Folder 59)
  - Congressional, testimony: texts, 1973-1974 (Box 48, Folder 60)
  - "Occupational Health: Myth or Reality," The New York Academy of Medicine, Section on Occupational Medicine, San Francisco: correspondence, 1974 January 23 (Box 48, Folder 61)
  - "Mandatory Versus Voluntary Physical Examinations in Industry," American Academy of Occupational Medicine, Annual Meeting, San Francisco: speech text, correspondence and related material, 1974 March 13 (Box 48, Folder 62)
  - "The Poverty of Affluence," American Journal of Public Health: reprint, 1975 January (Box 49, Folder 63)
  - Congressional testimony: texts, 1975-1976 (Box 49, Folder 64)
  - "A Nonentity: Occupational Health for Coalminers," Seventh Institute on Coal Mining Health, Safety and Research, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Blacksburg, Virginia: speech text, 1976 September 1 (Box 49, Folder 65)
  - "Toward Decent Rural Health Care," Second Annual Conference on Rural America, Des Moines: remarks, 1976 November 17 (Box 49, Folder 66)
  - "Informing the Worker - An Assessment," National Academy of Sciences, Washington, D.C.: speech text, 1976 December 2 (Box 49, Folder 67)
  - "Impact of National Health Insurance on Occupational Safety and Health," Seminar on Development of Clinic-Based Occupational Health and Safety Programs for Small Businesses: speech text, 1977 May 1 (Box 49, Folder 68)
  - "The Road We Have Come: Rural Health Needs and Non-Response," National Rural Health Conference, Washington, D.C.: speech text, 1977 December 5 (Box 49, Folder 69)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1977, undated (Box 49, Folder 70)
  - Statements: texts, 1977, undated (Box 49, Folder 71)